[{"question":"<p><strong>The &lsquo;Motto&rsquo; of the University of Lagos is?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The first and the Best","In deed and in truth","Dignity and Labour","Better by Far"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the Following is not the name of the Incumbent President of Nigeria?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Muhammadu","Buhari","Johnathan","General"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Name of the Organization that Provides Customers with Access to Internet is?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Cyber caf\u00e9","Internet Provider","Microsoft service provider","HTML editor"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Nigeria became a Republic in?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1960","1966","1963","1959"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The 2011 Presidential Election in Nigeria was held on?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["April 6, 2011","April 9, 2011","April 16, 2011","April 26, 2011"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the Following WAS NOT a Presidential candidate in the 2011 Presidential Election in Nigeria?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Nuhu Ribadu","Mohammed Buhari","Sekarau Ibrahim","Olusola Sakiri"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Chairman of the Economic and Financial Crimes Commission in Nigeria is?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Mrs. Farida Waziri","Mrs. Dora Akunyilu","Alh. Mohammed Buhari","None of the above"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Name of the WIFE of President Barack Obama of America is?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Michelle  Obama","Roseline Obama","Hillary Obama","none of the above"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>President Barack Obama of the United States of America is?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The 44th President of America","The 47th President of America","The 55th President of America","The 99th President of America","The 101th President of America"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Goals SCORED from the Offside Position in a Football Match ATTRACTS?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A penalty from the referee","Penalty by the award of one goal to the opponent","Nullification","None of the above"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Mammar Gaddafi was the President of?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Syria","Libya","Egypt","Malaysia","Yemen"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>9\/11 REFERS TO?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["September 9th , 2001 series of coordinated suicide attack on japan","September 9th , 2001 series of coordinated suicide attack on the USA","September 11th , 2009 series of coordinated suicide attack on the USA","September 11th , 2001 series of coordinated suicide attack on the USA"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Total number of VOTES scored by the WINNER of the 2011 Presidential Election in Nigeria was?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["30,379,159","22,495,187","12,214,853","12,495,187"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>INTERNET means?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Internal network","International network","Web-site","E-mail"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Who is the current Vice-President of Nigeria?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Atiku Abubakar","Prof Yemi Osibajo","Alh Namadi Sambo","Alh Jubril Aminu"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the Following States HAS NEVER BEEN The capital of the Federal Republic of Nigeria?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Lagos","Calabar","Lokoja","Abuja"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">The MOST NUMEROUS Ethnic group in the Northern 2\/3<sup>rd<\/sup> of Nigeria is ?<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Nupe","Tiv","Hausa-Fulani","Kanuri"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">The Presidential Election which was ANNULLED in Nigeria was held in?<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["June 1993","June 1994","July 1993","July 1994"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">What is the Full meaning of INEC?&nbsp;<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Independent National Electoral Commision","Independent National Election Commision","Independent National Electing Commision","Independent Nation Electoral Commision"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">The Last Gubernatorial Election in Nigeria Took place ON?&nbsp;<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["February 21, 2015","February 20, 2015","February 28, 2015","February 14, 2015","None of the above"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the Name of the Immediate Past Speaker of the House of Representative?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["David mark","Dimeji Longe","Dimeji Bankole","Bukola Saraki"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">Former Nigeria President Goodluck Jonathan was Former Governor of?<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Abia State","Ebonyi State","Bayelsa State","Cross river State","Anambra State"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">The Administrative Capital of South Africa is?<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Johannesburg","Durbar","Pretoria","Soweto","Cape Town"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">Senate President of Nigeria from May 2007-May 2011 WAS?<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Dimeji Bankole","David Mark","Alhaji Aliko dangote","Bukola Saraki"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which African Country was Called the &ldquo;GOLD COAST&rdquo;?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Cote d\u2019 evoir","Ghana","sierria-leone","Nigeria"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p style=\"text-align: left;\"><strong>Nigeria Presidential villa is located in ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Asokoro, Abuja","Dodan Barracks, Lagos","Obasanjo Farms, Otta","Aso Rock, Abuja"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>In which ethnic group the \"TALKING DRUM\" is commonly used<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Igbo Ethnic Group","Hausa Ethnic Group","Fulani Ethnic Group","Yoruba Ethnic Group","Ibibio Ethnic Group"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Nigeria flag consist of ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3 blocks of green, white and green","horizontal bands of green, white and green","3 vertical bands of green and white","3 horizontal bands of green, white and yellow"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Who named Nigeria<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Mungo Park","Lord Lugard","Flora Shaw","Charles Darwin","Lora Shaw"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the Following is NOT a Member of the Oil Producing States in Nigeria?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Bayelsa State","Cross River State","Lagos","Delta State"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Who INVENTED Telephone?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Graham Douglas","Alexander Graham Bell","Isaac Holloway","Antonio Meucci"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">The Main Accreditation body that Enforce Uniform Standard and Sets Admissions Capacity of Every University in Nigeria is?<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["The Nigeria University Commission","National Universities Commission (NUC)","The Federal Ministry of Education","Joint Admission Matriculation Board (JAMB)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">Electric bulb was Invented by?<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["John bulb","Thomas Alva Edison","Thomas Watt","Thomas Bulb"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Nigeria is organized into ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["36 States and a Federal Capital Territory (FCT) in Abuja","36 States minus the Federal Capital Territory (FCT) in Abuja","37 States and a Federal Capital Territory (FCT) in Abuja","36 States"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>University of Lagos is situated in ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Akoka, Yaba","Yaba, Akoka","Bariga, Yaba","Lagos"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Nigeria Accounts for ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1\/4th of Africa's people","1\/6th of Africa's people","1\/10th of Africa's people","1\/3rd of Africa's people"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The General Overseer of the Redeemed Christian Church of God in Nigeria is?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Pastor Williams Kumuyi","Pastor Enoch Adeboye","Pastor Benson Idahosa","Pastor wale Odukoya"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is NOT a pentecoastal church ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The Redeemed Christian Church of God","Deeper Life Bible Church","Mountain of Fire and Miracles Ministries","The Catholic Church"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The clock called BIG BEN can be found in ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Los-Angeles","Vancouver","Tokyo","United Kingdom"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is NOT in the National Anthem<\/strong><\/p>","options":["One Nation bound in Freedom","Arise o compatriots","To Serve our fatherland","We Hail Thee"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The MOST widely used languages in Nigeria are ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Fulani, Yoruba, and Igbo","Hausa, Igbo, Yoruba","Igbo, Yoruba and Pidgin","Pidgin, Yoruba, and Hausa"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of following African leaders IS NOT a Nobel prize winner ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Archbishop Desmond tutu","Mr Nelson Mandella","Prof. Wola Soyinka","Prof. Chinua Achebe"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Major ethnics group(s) in Southern Eastern Nigeria include ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Igbo, Kanuri, and Efik","Igbo, Ijaw and Ibibo","Igbo, Efik, and Ibibio","Igbo, Ijaw and Tiv"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>In the Human Respiration, Oxygen is INHALED, which of the following is EXHALED<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Carbon-monoxide","Oxygen","Carbon-dioxide","Carbon oxide"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following is NOT an ethnic group in South East in Nigeria<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Efik","Ijaw","Ibibio","None of the above"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The SMALLEST nation in the world is ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Vatican","Malaysia","Madagascar","Italy"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Number \"419\" refers to the Article _________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The American Criminal Code dealing with Internet Fraud","The Nigerian Criminal Code Act dealing with Fraud","The Russian Criminal Code dealing with Internet Fraud","The columbian Criminal Code dealing with Fraud"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Who won the 2011 Gubenatorial election in Lagos State ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Mr Babatunde Raji Fashola","Alhaji Bola Ahmed Tinubu","Mr Jimi Agbaje","Mrs Oluremi Tinubu"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">Albert Einsten, Sir Issac Newton and Charles Darwins have something in common?<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["They are all famous poet","They are all famous historians","They are all famous Artist","They are all famous Scientist"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">The Current Chairman of INEC is?<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Prof. Maurice Iwu","Prof. Rasheed muniru jega","Mrs. Amina Zakari","Prof. Atahiru Jega"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri,sans-serif;\">The Nigeria Civil War was from?<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["1967-1969","1967-1970","1967-1971","1968-1971"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">The Flag of Nigeria was First designed in and Officially Hosted in?<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["1959 and 1960","1960 and 1959","1970 and 1959","1971 and 1970"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is NOT True about Computers?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Process information electronically to produce data","Computer are programmable so we can tell them what to do","Computer also include small programmed systems found in some appliance such as phones, microwave, ovens and video recorder","Computer consist of Hardware and software"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">____________&nbsp; &nbsp;is used to read Pages Setup on the Internet?<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["IP address","Satelite Communication","Web conferencing","E-mail"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\"><strong>which of the following methods of communication may be inconvenienced by time zone ?&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;<\/strong><\/span><\/p>","options":["post","fax","E- mail","Mobile telephone"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">All but one of the following are actions for dealing with Viruses in your Computer&nbsp; &nbsp;<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["scanning of incoming mail","changing password regularly","using filtrating software to prevent downloads of computer programs","Not opening suspicious  e-mail or attachment","not allowing others to bring in floppy disks or flash drives to your computer system without scanning"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">Search Engines on the Internet help to Search for Information by?<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Looking for heading of web document","Looking for words inside web document","Searching other search engine","None of the options","All of the options  ."],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">The Public Sector in Nigeria does not include?<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["The Army","The central Bank of Nigeria","The business owned by individual members of the public","The public"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">May 29th in Nigeria is celebrated as&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Independence day","Mother\u2019s day","Democracy day","hanging over day"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">The Corporate Affairs Commission in Nigeria is responsible for<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Taxation of companies in Nigeria","Registration of companies in Nigeria","Closing down companies who do not pay tax 1961","None of the above"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">Government&nbsp; spends taxes on?<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Provisional of health service","Education","Defence","All of above","None of the Above"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">One of the Following Countries is NOT a Republic<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["USA","Nigeria","China","UK"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">The Millennium&nbsp; Development &nbsp;Goals Include?<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Reduce those suffering from hunger  and poverty","Ensure all children get primary education","Stop the spread of aids","All of the options"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">The G8 is a meeting of eight rich countries including<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["USA  , UK Canada  south Africa and france","UK , Germany , USA , Japan and Brazil","China , USA , UK  Canada  and Germany","UK , USA , Italy, France ,Germany"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">The 9\/11 attack killed nearly 3,000 people and destroyed the&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["IMF office","World bank","World Trade Centre","Wall Street"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Winner of the 2011 African youth Championship, u-20 football fiesta held in South-Africa is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Nigeria","Mali","Cameroon","Egypt"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">Which of the following is not a political party in Nigeria<\/span><\/strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\"><br \/><\/span><\/p>","options":["Action congress of Nigeria","Peoples democratic party","Labour party","Republican party"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">The Capital of Cape Verde Is?<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Pirar","Praia","Paria","Praai","All of the Options"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">Brazil is a country in<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Africa","America","Eruope","Australia"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">The Current Governor of the Central Bank of Nigeria is?<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Sanusi lamido","Chukwuma solude","Godwin Emefiele","Erastus akingbola"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">Which of the following died while in office as a Nigeria ruler<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Alhaji umaru Yar\u2019Aduaa","General sani abacha","General muritala muhammed","All of the above"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">The Current Prime Minister of British is?<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Mr Tony  Blair","Mr David Cameron","Mr Gordon black","Theresa May"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">Prince William and kate were married at westminister abbey ,London on&nbsp; april<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["11th Aprill, 2011","29th Aprill, 2011","1st  May, 2011","None of the above"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">Which of the following is not a search engine<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Google","Excite","a Vista","Yahoo"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">Which of the following is not a current telecom service provider in Nigeria<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Starcoms","Airtel","MTN","Celtel"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">www&nbsp; used in web address on internet means<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["world wide web","world  wave web","word wave web","world wide wave"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">The first prime minister in Nigeria is<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Dr Nnamdi Azikiwe","Alhaji Shehu Shagari","Alhaji Tafawa Balewa","Lord lugard"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">The blue buses using special lanes in lagos are commonly referred&nbsp;&nbsp; to as BRT buses. What does BRT means?<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Babatunde raji transport","Babatunde raji transit","Bus rapid transit","Blue rapid transport"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">HAITI is a country in<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["North America","South America","Asia","None of the above"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">The first Nigerian woman to win an Olympic medal is&nbsp;<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Chioma Ajunnwa","Nojeem Mayegun","Fidelis Okoro","None of the above"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">The first Nigerian to win the heavy weight boxing championship of the world is<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Simon Joe","Hogan Kid Bassey","Samuel Peter","Bash Ali"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">The first television station was established in Nigeria in<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["1959","1960","1961","1962"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following two statements does not explain the word &ldquo;surfing&rdquo;?<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I. A sport in which the individual rides on the crest or along tunnel of a wave<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>II. Exploration of the web (www)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["I only","II only","I & II","Neither I nor II"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">The Headquarters of the United Nations is in<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Addis-Ababa","New York","Washington","London"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">The head of common wealth Nations is<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Queen Elizabeth of England II","Mr. Ban-Ki Moon","Mr. Kofi Anan","Prof. Jerry Gana"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">The university of Lagos was established in<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["1962","1960","1961","1959"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">Where is the Sahara desert ?<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["America","Europe","Asia","Africa"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">Which of the following is not in the newspaper circulation in Nigeria ?<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["The Guardian","The punch","The Nation","LeFigaro"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">Which country will host the 2018 FIFA World Cup Football?<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Russia","France","Qatar","Nigeria","South-Africa"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">_____________is the most populous African nation.<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Kenya","South African","Nigeria","Ghana"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">Nigeria&rsquo;s national telephone code is<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["080","234","233","009"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">Nigeria population is currently estimated to be about<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["100million","140million","190million","200million"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>An Institution which seeks to Redress People&rsquo;s Grievances against Abuse of Administrave Power is the?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ombudsman","Judiciary","Directorate of public prosecution","Judicial service commission"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the Major Problems which spelt Doom for Nigeria Airways was?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Embezzlement of fund","Corruption","Lack of patriotism","All of the above"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Main Cause of Infrastructure Decay in Nigeria is?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Illitracy","Disobedience","Lack of maintenance","Political instability"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Idea of making Local government the Third tier Government was Initiated by?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Abdulsalam Regime","Alhaji Shehu Shagari Regime","Murtala Obasanjo Regime","Ibrahim Babangida Regime"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Public Corporation is similar to the Joint stock company BECAUSE?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The chairman is also the managing director","The shares of which are traded on a public stock exchange","The two are legal entities","They share the same market"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the FOLLOWING statement both describe a Public Corporation?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["It is an organ  of government  responsible for executing the policies of government","It is a local body that renders services on local basis","It us a company whose shares are traded freely on a stock exchange.","It is a body owned by member of th public"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the Measures that will Enhance the status of the Local Government as a Third Tier of Government is?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The creation of more local government","upgrading the local government to statehood","Drafting of separate constitution for local government .","Deduction of local government share of federal allocation directly from source"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Main Function of the Administrative Class of the Civil Service INCLUDE?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["policy making","Implement of government policies","Enhancement of laws for the ministries","All of the above"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>To Enhance the Independence of the Federal Public Services Commission, Member should?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Be elected from a national party","Take oath of celibacy","Neither belong to the judiciary nor executive branch of government","Be appointed by the non aligned movement"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Public Corporations in Nigeria are Subjected to the Control?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The Judiciary","The Legislative","The State","Public service commission"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Engineer and Architects in the Civil Services fall into the?<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Professional class","Technical class","Higher technical class","The manipulative class"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Before the 1979 local Government Reform, One of the Defective Features of the Local Government in Nigeria that?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["they had no functions to perform","They had no legal personality","They had no chairmen to pilot  their affairs","They had no political aspiration"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Dismissal of a Staff in the Ministry for Official Misconduct is the Prerogative is?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The permanent   secretary","The personnel manager","The  minister","The public service commission"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Greatest head-ache affecting Revenue Generation by NEPA is?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Debt owned it by government department\u2019s and official","Refusal of NEPA men to generate fee","Its instability  to employ accountant","None of the above"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The First Local Government System Adopted in Nigeria by The Regional Government WAS?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The French prefectorial  system","The Indian local  government system","The Russian socialist system","The British council system"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Relationship between Staffs of the Civil service in the Discharge of their Duties is EXPECTED to BE?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Personal  and unofficial","Official and non-personal","Casual and  inconsistent","Illogical and sporadic"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>To be Promoted from one Grade level to another, a Staff must first ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["to the Nigeria Apply export  promotion council","Petition the civil service commission","Be in the president or governor\u2019s  list  commission by his or her departmental head","Be recommended  to the public services"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the First TV station in Nigeria?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Western Nigerian Government Broadcasting Corporation (WNTV)","Nigerian Television Authority (NTA)","Ogun State Television (OGTV)","Africa independent television (AIT)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Following were Reasons why the Febuary 14 and 28 were prosponed by INEC EXCEPT?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["More time to train more staff","More people to collect their PVCs and vote","All of the above","None of the above"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Permanent Voter Cards (PVCs) that Voters used to vote were made in<\/strong><\/p>","options":["China","Japan","America","Ethopia"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Main Function of the Legislature is?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["To Implement law","To Enforce law","To Make law","To Interprets law"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Saifawa constituted the ruling dynasty in?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Zazzau","Dahomey","Kanem-Borno","Zamfara"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Nigeria&rsquo;s vice president during the Second Republic was<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Dr. Alex Ekwueme","Dr Chuba Okadigbo","Dr Nnamdi Azikwe","Chief Emeka Ojukwu"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Saifawa dynasty came to an end in the year<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1820","1846","1860","1865"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The strongest military power in nineteenth-century Yorubaland was<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ijaye","Ibadan","Ife","Ijebu"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Samori Toure employed scorched earth tactics in his resistance against the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["British","French","German","Portuguese"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Who among the following merged all British companies in 1879 to form the United Africa Company?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Alexander Miller","John Holt","Tubman Goldie","James Pinnock"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of this succeeded Oranmiyan in Benin?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ewuare","Esigie","Ozolua","Eweka"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Nigeria became a republic in the year<\/b><\/p>","options":["1963","1960","1961","1976"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Idris Aloma was a ruler in&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Zaria","Kano","Kanem-Bornu","Songhai"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The mystical hero of the Nupe was?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Esigie","Tsoedeas","Bawo","Bagauda"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The office of the prime minister is the same as that of president<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Chief of Army Staff","Head of Government","Head of Parliament","Speaker of the house"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a presidential system of government, the ministers are;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Collectively responsible to the national assembly","Individually responsible to the national assembly","Individually responsible to the president","Individually responsible to the electorates","None of the options"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>In Nigeria, political violence is synonymous with<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Military rule","Opposition parties","Ethnic militia","Election results","INEC"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of this has the primary duty for the privatization of government companies in Nigeria<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Central bank","National planning commission","Due process office","Bureau of Public Enterprise","Debt Management office"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the following political parties was in power at the centre in Nigeria between 1979-1983<\/strong><\/p>","options":["SDP","NCNC","NPN","UPN","PDP"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a parliamentary system;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The president and the prime minister are members of government cabinet","The cabinet is headed by Prime Minister","The cabinet is headed by the president","The president and the prime minister are not members of government cabinet"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Under the 1999 constitution of Nigeria, one of the following is not in the line of succession to the presidency of the country<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The Vice President","The Senate President","Secretary to the Government of the Federation","The speakers of the House of Representatives"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>A sitting of the legislature usually comes to a close through<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Adjournment","Rising","Order","Suspension","Dissolution"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>An ideology is by definition<\/strong><\/p>","options":["set of principles","set of opinions","set of epic","political belief","individual opinion"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The internal security of a nation is primarily the responsibility of the?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The ministry of internal affairs","Ministry of defence","The police","The National Assembly members","INEC"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The primary function of the ministry of defence is?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["making peace","creating social awareness","stopping visible action","Higher Education for defence services personnel.","None of the Options"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Because of incessant political violence western region was reffered to as?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Owambe region","Agbekoya","Wild wild west","OPC","Western power"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The area of the lower Niger fell into the British sphere of influence largely through the activities of the?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Lower Niger Company","Royal Niger Company","British Niger company","United Africa company","United Trading company"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The seat of the Federal government during the Fourth Republic was?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Lokoja","Calabar","Abuja","Lagos","Ibadan"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these has not been a head of the electoral body in Nigeria<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Justice Muhammed Uwais","Justice Ovie Whisky","Chief Anthony Ani","Prof. Eme Awa","Chief Abel Guobadia"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The apartheid state in South Africa was notorious because?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Of the periodic elections","The people were fed with bread daily","Violence was used to oppress the blacks","The whites did not offer employment to illiterate blacks","All of the options"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following two organs of government continued to function throughout military rule in Nigeria<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Bureaucracy and the executive","Legislative and the executive","Executive and the judiciary","Legislature and the judiciary","Legislature and Executive"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>A permanent civil service?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Makes old people to continue in government","Makes for continuity in government","Makes partisanship to continue in government","Makes civil organizations to control government","Makes for corruption in government"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Sovereign authority in a democracy is exercised by the?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Electorate","Military","Legislature","Executive","Judiciary"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of these countries is not a member of ECOWAS?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Nigeria","Mali","Morrocco","Togo","Ghana"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Most federal constitutions are?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Flexible","Written by one man","Imported from other countries","Without provision for amendment","Rigid"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these countries is NOT a function of the Nigerian Legislature?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Control of public funds","Checks on the executives","Siphoning of Public funds","Representation of their constituencies","Making of laws"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Under the presidential system of government, ministers are:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Appointed from among the members of the legislature","Appointed by the President subject to confirmation by the legislature","Nominated by the legislature and announced by the President","Elected by the legislature from amongst the electorate","Elected by the electorate from among the legislature"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The headquarters of A.U is in?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Abuja","Cairo","Accra","Addis Ababa","Port Harcourt"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The 1999 constitution guarantees what percentage of proceeds from oil revenue to the producing states?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["25%","13.5%","13%","15%","15.35%"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Willink&nbsp; Commission of 1957 was set up to tackle<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Minority complaints","Majority complaints","Ethnic chauvinism","Independence questions","Nationality troubles"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Nazism was an ideology of?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Extreme nationalism once practiced in Germany","National liberation was practiced in Cuba","Extreme racism once practiced in South Africa","Cultural evaluation once practiced in China","Islamic fundamentalism once practiced in Iraq"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Socialism is all about<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Social issues","Social sciences","The socialization of means of production","The history of production","All of the options"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>An example of a country with a prime minister is?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Brazil","United Kingdom","Germany","South Africa","Ghana"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The first democratically elected Vice President of Nigeria was?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Alhaji Shehu Aliyu Shagari","Dr. Nnamdi Azikwe","Sir Tafawa Balewa","Chief Obafemi Awolowo","Dr. Alexander Ekwuene"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>According to Marxist theory, those who own and control the means of production in a capitalist system constitute the?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Stock owners","Shareholders","Exploiters Class","Bourgeois Class","Workers Class"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following two political parties were formed by Obafemi Awolowo?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["AD and AC","AG and UPN","AD and AG","UPN and NNDP","AG and AC"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Under the 1999 constitution, the tenure of local government chairmen is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["As set down under relevant laws of each state","Uniform across the country","As determined by the ruling party in the state","As fixed by the government of the state","Determined by the councilors in each local government"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following is one of the agents of Socialization<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Books","Tourism","Good Health","Mass media","Vendor"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Socialism creates?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Wealth for the rich","Egalitarianism","Equalization","Opportunity to steal government property","None of the options"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these laws sought to make Nigeria a unitary State<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Decree 34 of 1966","Decree 34 of 1963","Decree 34 of 1960","Decree 34 of 1975","Decree 34 of 1970"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Under the 1999 constitution, which of these states has the highest number of local government in the country?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Katsina","Oyo","Kano","Lagos","Borno"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>A cabinet system was practiced in Nigeria under the leadership of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Alhaji Shehu Shagari","Chief Obafemi Awolowo","Sir Tafawa Balewa","Gen Yakubu Gowon","Chief Ernest Shonikan"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Colonial administration in West Africa was basically a rule of?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Might","Right","Light","None of the option","All of the option"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The first election conducted in Nigeria was in?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1979","1922","1999","1960"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the percentage of the federation account that accrues to local government?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["30%","15%","18%","20%","25%"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of this administration first recognized the local governments as the third tier of government in Nigeria<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Gowon regime","Muritala regime","Shagari regime","Buhari regime"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Who was the governor of Western Nigeria during the 1962 emergency?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Chief Adisa Akinloya","Dr M.A Majekodunmi","Chief Odeleye Fadahunsi","Chief Richard Akinjide","Chief Remi Fani-Kayode"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the main issues of Federalism in Nigeria is?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Criminal headship","Revenue collection","Education policy","Recruitment into the armed forces","Fiscal policy"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>An efficient government needs?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Regular inflow of income from oil","Strong student unionism","A strong and united ruling class","An uninterrupted tenure","A dynamic armed forces"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>In the First Republic, a major problem of Nigeria&rsquo;s federalism was?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Military intervention politics","Politicization of the military","Ethnic politics","Lopsided civil service","Dependent judiciary"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following countries EXCEPT ______ were members of the front line states<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Nigeria","Malawi","Zambia","Tanzania","South Africa"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following is NOT a function of political parties<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Presenting candidate for election","Opposition to the government","Interest aggregation","Rigging of elections","Formation of the government"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>According to Marxis theory, those who sell their labour power in order to live are the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Labourers","Slaves","Workers","Serfs","Peasants"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The term rule of law means<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Only the president rules by the law","Nobody is under the law","Loyal govern by the laws","Everybody is above the law","Nobody is above the law"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Power is different from influence in that<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The one is persuasive while the other is directive","The one is harmful while the other is coercive","The one is desirous while the other is ambitious","The one is coercive while the other is persuasive","The one is harmless while the other is disruptive"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Public cooperation in Nigeria was established to<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Provide settlement for supporters of the president and his party","Provide government functionaries with avenue to loot the treasury","Provide social amenities to the people","Provide sources of diverting government revenues","Convince the people t vote for the government party"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Nigeria's flag is made up of?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1 colour","2 colour","3 colour","4 colour","All of the options"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Socialism aims at<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Legalizing elections","Eliminating the president","Abolishing poverty","Making students work hard","None of the options"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The early nationalist movement in west Africa was led by<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Negro Africans","Missionary Africans","Educated Africans","Traditional rulers","African civil servants"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The oldest among the armed forces of Nigeria is?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The police","Civil Defence corps","The Army","The Navy","The Air Force"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the following is a limitation of the rule of law<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The principle of the supremacy of the law","The principle of equality before the law","The principle of impartiality before the law","The principle of immunity from the law","The principle of the separation of power"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Pressure groups help to consolidate democracy by<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Representing the professional groups","Being in charge of elections","Not allowing misrule","Allowing the assembly to rule with the judiciary","Providing the platform for confrontation with the government"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Under the 1999 constitution of Nigeria, the following is NOT a member of a political party<\/strong><\/p>","options":["President of the country","Governor of a state","Member of the national assembly","Member of the state house of assembly","State commissioner of Police"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Local government council in Nigeria are headed by<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Mayors","Traditional rulers","Chairmen","Commissioners","Councilors"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The JUNE 12 presidential election was conducted by the?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["National election Commission of Nigeria","National Electoral Commission","Independent National Electoral Commission","Nigerian Electoral Commission","Federal Electoral Commission"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The structure of the civil service is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Circular","Rectangular","Flat","Pyramidal","Conical"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The vice president of Chief Olusegun Obasanjo during the 2007 electioneering campaign was?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ahlhaji Umaru Yara\u2019dua","Alhaji Muhammadu Buhari","Alhaji Abubakar Atiku","Senate Ahmadu Ali","None of the options"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The legislative organ of the federal government in the field Republic was the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Legislative Assembly","National Assembly","Parliament","Federal House","National House"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>A major factor that differenciates the president from the parliamentary system is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Executive election","Judicial power","Organs of government","Collective responsibility","Legislative practices"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The general election that was ushered in independence was conducted in<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1963","1951","1959","1960","1958"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The primary function of the Armed Forces of a country is to?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Remove bad leaders","Defend the territorial integrity of the country","Maintain honourable and disciplines officers","Protect the political leaders","None of the options"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The 1999 constitution recognizes how many local government in Nigeria?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["844","840","774","750","960"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Nigerian civil service was first regionalized by the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Independence constitution","Republican constitution","Richards\u2019s constitution","Littleton constitution","Clifford constitution"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a parliamentary system, the cabinet holds office at the pleasure of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The president","The executive council","The electorate","The judiciary","The legislature"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The first Prime Minister of Nigeria was?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Chief Obafemi Awolowo","Dr Nnamdi Azikiwe","Chief Anthony Enahoro","Sir Tafawa balewa","Dr Yakubu Gowon"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>All this constitutions were republican EXCEPT<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1960","1963","1999","1989","1996"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the Country is a Unitary state<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ghana","Ethopia","USA","Canada","Brazil"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Delegated legislation is necessary because these are issues<\/strong><\/p>","options":["On which legislators cannot agree","That are very emotional to legislators","That have to be considered only when the legislators are on recess","That are too personal for legislators to consider","That are technical and have to be handled by experts"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>&nbsp;In the older days, maintenance of peace in igbo land was a responsibility of?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Eze Igbo","Age grades","Ndigbo society","The Eze in council","The assembly of the Ezes"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of this principle revenue allocation would favour a state like Lagos?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Land mass","Number of buildings","Population","Derivation","Number of businessmen"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following was not a British colonial territory in West Africa?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ghana","Nigeria","Gambia","Gabon","Sierra Leone"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The official that represents Nigerian president in Ghana is called?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Head of state in Ghana","Ambassador","High commissioner","Chief of staff","Foreign secretary"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The twin tower in America was destroyed in September 11<sup>th<\/sup> of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1999","2000","2001","2002","2003"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The term rule of law is applicable only in those<\/strong><\/p>","options":["States where laws are made","States where laws are applied","States where laws are implemented","States where laws are bassed","States where laws are supreme"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Aminu Kano was the leader of the following two political parties?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["NPN and NPP","PRP and PRM","NEPU and PRP","MPC and NEPU","NEPU and UMBC"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following makes human right activism difficult in Nigeria?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Nigeria\u2019s clossness to Cameroon","The exploitation of oil and gas","The volume of business activities","Violent and reckless state","All of the options"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Under communism, there would be no<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Production","Head of state","Class stratification","State boundary","Super markets"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Two houses of parliamentarian mean<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Senate and representatives","Lower and upper house","Commons and lords","All of the options"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Nigeria&rsquo;s current national assembly was adopted when one of the following was Nigerian leader?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Gen Ibrahim Babangida","Sir Lord Lugard","Dr Nnamdi Azikiwe","Gen. Olusegun Obasanjo","Alhaji Shehu Shagari"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following encourages democracy?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A strong president","Multiple voting system","An electoral body headed by a police officer","Freedom of choice","Citizens right to confident election riggers"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>How many additional states were created in 1991?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["8","10","9","6","11"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Government by wealthy people is known as?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Democracy","Phitocracy","Oligarchy","Aristocracy","Dictatorship"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The concept of sovereignty is best defined by the?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Supremacy of the state","Supremacy of the president","Supremacy of the legislature","Supremacy of the executive","Supremacy of the judiciary"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>A major weakness of unitary system of government is that?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["It runs a country as a single entity","It allows for easy amendment of the constitution of a country","It often permits the marginalization of military groups","It does not often permit opposition groups","It encourages ethnicity in politics"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Human rights are guaranteed by<\/strong><\/p>","options":["UNO","Customary law","The constitution","Apartheid law","English law"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The first secretary general of the OAU was?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Gen. Yakubu Gowon","Chief Emeka Ayanoku","Mr Diallo Telli","Gen Ibrahim Babaginda","Kwame Nkrumah"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The precursor to the Africa Union (AU) was<\/strong><\/p>","options":["None of the options","ECOWAS","OSAS","OAU","ADB"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a presidential system of government, the executive checks the legislature through<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Executive review","Executive order","Executive power","Veto power","Mandate power"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The principle of separation of power implies that?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The national assembly cannot impeach the president","The president cannot sack his ministers arbitrarily","Power belongs to every organ of government","Power is shared between the different organs of the state","Power is competed for by all the organs of government"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the following is usually used on matters of foreign relations?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Propaganda","Prayer and fasting","Declaration of public holidays","Committee and panel reports","All of the options"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The first governor of Midwest region was?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Chief Obafemi Awolowo","Brig. S.O Ogbemuda","Chief Dennis Osadebe","Chief Anthony Gnahiro","Chief Jerome Mariero"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The ideology of scientific socialism was<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Adam smith","Karl Marx","Chairman Mao","John smith"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following does not function under a military regime?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Colleges of education","Private media","Legislature","Police College","Student unionism"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The concept of power means?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The desire to compel obedience","The capacity to compel obedience","The height to compel obedience","The force of the people","The apparatus of the state"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The orientation of early nationalism in Nigeria was?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Revolutionary","Antagonistic","Reformatory","Reactionary","Radical"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Chief Olusegun Obasanjo has been Nigeria&rsquo;s leader for a total of?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["10 years","8 years","11 years","4 years","21 years"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Who is most associated with the doctrine of separation of Powers?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Mars","Bentham","Rousseau","Montesquieu","Hegel"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following except ONE is a pressure group in Niegria?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Nigerian Union of Teachers","Civil liberties organization","Institute of chartered accountants of Nigeria","Civil liberties organization","Democracy watch"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these revenue allocation principle will greatly favour Adamawa state over Imo state<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Population","Land mass","Derivation","Number of schools","Number of voters"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Under the 1999 constitution, the relationship of the local government to the state and federal government is supposed to be<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Co-ordinate","Superordinate","Subordinate","Superordinate","Insubordinate"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>A candidate who loses his deposit in a election<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Failed to win a minimum percentage of votes set by the laws","Cannot see the money he has kept with his campaign managers","Is duped by his campaign team","Is defrauded by his bank during campaigns","Must have kept his money in a failed bank"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following countries were synonymous with apartheid<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Nigeria and Ghana","All of the options","South Africa and Zambia","South Africa and Southern Rhodesia","Kenya and Malawi"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the following is NOT in Eastern Europe<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Russia","Hungary","Sweden","Slovakia","Serbia"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of this is a public corporation in Nigeria?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["ICAN","UAC","PZ","NNPC","UNDP"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Who was made the General Secretary of the NCNC when Azikiwe became the president?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Herbert Macaulay","Ernest Ikoli","Ogedengbe Macaulay","H.O Davies","Bode Thomas"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>In which continent is mount everest?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Asia","North America","South America","Europe","Africa"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following groups fall into the Civil Service?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The police, the army, and the air force","Employees of NEPA, NNPC and NRC","Employees of ministries of finance, education and transportation","All of the above"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Trebuchet MS', sans-serif;\">The recruitment or appointment of the permanent secretary is one of the duties of<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["The federal public service commission","The state civil service commission","The executive","The National Assembly"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>In the organizational structure of the ministry or government department, offices and&nbsp; positions are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Hierarchically arranged","Diagonally arranged","Secretly arranged","Haphazardly arranged"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The government maintains monopoly over certain services for<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Selfish reasons","Security and strategic reasons","Undisclosed reasons","All of the above"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Ministers of local government and chieftancy affairs were abolished in Nigeria by<\/strong><\/p>","options":["General Yakubu Gowon","General Murtala Mohammed","President  Ibrahim Babangida","General Olusegun Obasanjo"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Policy analysis, policy implementation and plan setting are some of the functions&nbsp; of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The legislature","The executive","The local government","The civil service"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Public corporations can be controlled through<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Riots","Public opinion","Civil disobedience","None of the above"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The general supervision of a public corporation is carried out by&nbsp;the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Board of directors","Board of trustees","Managing director","Secretary of the board"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The local government in Nigeria is created&nbsp;to<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Create more civil service jobs","Encourage competition and rivalry among communities","Bring the government nearer to the people","Prevent the creation of more  states"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Civil Service embraces all workers&nbsp;in<\/strong><\/p>","options":["All private corporations","Public and private companies","Government  ministries","Public corporations"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The effective operation of the Civil Service in Nigeria is mostly hampered&nbsp;by<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Inadequate training of personnel","Corruption and inefficiency","Debt burden and redundancy","Poor infrastructure"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Bureau of Public Enterprises is charged with the responsibility&nbsp;for<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Privatization  and commercialization","Generating revenue","Eradicating poverty","Providing  employment opportunities"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Financial allocation to a local government by the Federal or a State government to supplement the cost of a project is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Revenue allocation","Reimbursement","Statutory allocation","Matching grant"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>A permanent Civil Service<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Makes  continuity  in  government possible","Makes civil servants arrogant","Promotes ethnic domination","Is undemocratic"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>One form of control exercised over public corporations is the requirement that their annual reports be laid before<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Parliament for scrutiny","All the political parties","All the local authorities in the   country","A joint committee of the executive and  parliament"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Anonymity of the Civil Service means that the Civil Servant must:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Serve any government impartially","Be politically neutral","Be politically neutral","Not receive the credit or blame for any good or bad policy"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The local government reforms of 1976 in Nigeria were designed to:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Decentralize authority","Enlist grass-root support","Achieve even development","All of the above"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Bye-laws made by local authorities can be declared unconstitutional only by the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Local  government  service commission","Ministry of local government and chieftaincy  affairs","Courts","Attorney-General"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Mass retrenchment of workers in the public and private sectors is most likely to result in<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Political  stability","Economic survival","High rate of armed robbery, pilfering and political instability","Electoral  malpractices"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not a source of local government&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;revenue<\/strong><\/p>","options":["State and federal government grants","Licensing of cars and lorries","Market stall fees","Returns on investment"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the major reasons for setting up public corporations is to<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Maximize profit","Compete with private companies","Provide essential services","Encourage patronage"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>All of the following are functions of the civil service except<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Making laws","Implementing  policies","Preparing financial estimates","Implementing edicts"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>One factor which militates against the effective functioning of the Civil Service is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Delegated  legislation","Political  interference","Judicial inference","Political  stability"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Being the third tier of government, the local government is therefore<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Subordinate to state and federal government","Antagonistic to state and federal   government","Co-ordinate to state and federal government","All of the above"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>One major problem facing public corporations in Nigeria is:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Political parties","Excessive patriotism","Government interference","Judicial manipulation"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Most of the reasons given for the establishment of public corporations in Nigeria are being contradicted by the current wave of:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Privatization  and commercialization","Legalization and nationalization","Judicial and legislative competence","Rigging and electoral brouhaha"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The recruitment, promotion and discipline of civil servants in Nigeria is the responsibility of:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Board  of Directors","Civil  Service  Commission","The president","Ministry of Labour and  Productivity"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Engineers and architects in the Civil Service fall into the:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Professional class","Technical class","Higher technical class","The manipulative class"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The main functions of the administrative class of the Civil Service include:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Policy making","Implementation  of  government policies","Enactment of laws for the  ministries","All of the above"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The relationship between staffs of the civil service in the discharge of their duties is expected to be:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Personal  and unofficial","Official and non-personal","Casual and inconsistent","Illogical and sporadic"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The first local government system adopted in Nigeria by the regional government was:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The French prefectorial system","The Indian local government system","The Russian Socialist system","The British Council system"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The idea of making the local government the third tier of government was initiated by:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Abdusalam Abubakar regime","Alhaji Shehu Shagari regime","Murtala\/ Obasanjo regime","Ibrahim Babangida regime"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Before the 1976 local government reforms, one of the defective features of the local governments in Nigeria was that:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["They had no functions to perform","They had no  legal personality","They had no chairmen to pilot their affairs","They had no political  aspiration"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the major problems which spelt doom for Nigeria Airways was:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Embezzlement of fund","Corruption","Lack of patriotism","All of the above"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The main cause of infrastructure decay in Nigeria is:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Illiteracy","Disobedience","Lack of maintenance culture","Political  instability"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the measures that will enhance the status of the local government as a third tier of government is:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The creation of more local government areas","Up-grading the local government to statehood","Drafting of separate constitution for local  government","Deduction of local government share of federal allocation directly from source"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>To enhance the independence of the federal public service commission, members should:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Be elected from a national party","Take oath of celibacy","Neither belong to the legislative nor executive branch of    government","Be appointed by the non-aligned movement"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>To be promoted from one grade level to another, a staff must first:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Apply to the Nigeria export promotion  council","Petition the civil service  commission","Be in the president or governor\u2019s  list","Be recommended to the public service commission by his or her departmental head"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The dismissal of a staff in the ministry for official misconduct is the prerogative is:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The permanent secretary","The personnel manager","The minister","The Public Service  Commission"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The greatest head-ache affecting revenue generation by NEPA is:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Refusal of NEPA men to collect revenue","Its instability to employ accountants","Debts owed  it  by  government  departments and officials","None of the above"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Public Corporations in Nigeria are subject to the control of:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The judiciary","The minister in charge","The parliament","Public  Service Commission"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The public corporation is similar to the joint stock company because:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The chairmen is also the managing director","Their administrative centres are far from their main  factories","The two are legal entities","They share the same market"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following statements both describes a public corporation:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["It is an organ of government responsible for executing the  policies  of  government","It is a local body that renders services on a local basis","It is a legal body established by an act of state to provide essential services","It is a body owned by members of the public"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>&lsquo;Red tapism&rsquo; can be explained as:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The decentralized way of taking   decision","A flexible way by which government decisions are taken","The rigid adherence to routines by civil servants","Management by objectives"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>An institution which seeks to redress people&rsquo;s grievances against abuse of administrative power is the:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ombudsman","Judiciary","Directorate of Public  Prosecution","Judicial Service Commission"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>A statutory corporation is under the supervision of:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The Chief Justice","The commissioner of police","A minister","A local government chairman"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>To which class of the civil service does the causal or manual labour force belong:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The technical class","The casual class","The manipulative class","The higher technical class"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The first person to develop the atomic bomb was:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Albert Einstein","Charles De Gaulle","Thomas Jefferson","T.S. Elliot"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>The wavelength of ultraviolet radiation is 400mm if the speed of light in air is 3x10<sup>8<\/sup>m\/s; then the frequency of the ultraviolet radiation<\/strong><\/p>","options":["13 x 10<sup>15<\/sup>Hz","75 x 10<sup>5<\/sup>Hz","12 x 10<sup>10<\/sup>Hz","75 x 10<sub>7<\/sub>Hz"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"<p><strong>Nigeria has ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["102 Ethnic groups","250 Ethnic groups","Over 250 ethnic groups","Over 102 ethnic groups"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the following is NOT a Nigerian music ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Fuji","Yo-Pop","Afrojuju","Highlife"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">The Full meaning of CNN, the American television station is?<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Cable News Network","Cable National News","Cable Network News","All of the Options"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">Nigeria Ranks in African&rsquo;s GDP&nbsp;<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["First","Second","Third","Fourth"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong><span style=\"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;\">Which of the Following is NOT a Feature of the e-mail?<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Learn to Use an Address book","Use a signature","None of the Options","Can be sent at anytime","Set up auto responders"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"}]